okay well folks today we have the
Megalodon herself we've gotten Megan
Elam in the stew today
I've been called Megalodon and so long
I'll call you that I also want to also
wanted to say stew I really like you
notice how like a lot of young people
studio I'm in this date Oh people might
call me yes we've got Megan women here
today Megan has been one of my very
close friends for quite some time we've
lived together we've been BFF jill's me
her and Shelley just the trio of
awesomeness and Bentleys I guess he's
the fourth person worked Rio - Bentley
is also with us today we didn't get him
a mic but he agreed to breathe as loudly
as he can near Megan's so you guys can
hear him so Megan
man how are you how are you today doing
good doing Christmas my mom tonight is
very excited be fun down in Vancouver
yes you came all the way up here to hang
out with me for a few but it'll be back
on the way home because you recently
moved to Portland not so recently now I
guess yeah key believe it's almost been
two and half years
that's weird actually yeah cuz I moved
out from cast rock with you guys and
then went straight to Portland and it's
been almost two and a half years yeah
next September we got be three well like
two not quite two enough years but and
how do you feel do you feel like you
belong in Portland yet um I love
Portland I think it's like at the right
time of my life um being like single and
living in like a studio in downtown
Portland just that's something I always
wanted to do and accomplish
um but it's very interesting being in a
big city because you don't have like
that sense of community like you do in
real small town so I love Portland
I probably after I'm going to be moving
out of Portland actually in September
ish and I don't know if I'll move back
to downtown we'll see I'm thinking
Vancouver but it's been really fun it's
fun being close to every yeah we'll see
how much you miss it like you have such
a good location like you're so close to
all these cool yeah I just walked
everything like walk I like walk
my workout to Orangetheory and it's like
two minutes from my front door plenty of
places go get a get a bite to eat and
stuff too and you can also walk -
there's that Dyke right by your house -
it's always good to be able to like oh
I'm gonna go for a run I don't have to
drive there I can just walk to the start
of my run literally I just walk out my
front door and it's the run like it
started yeah we're not important is
getting so busy and it's such a cliche
thing to say I suppose but it seems like
it's leaking towards this way yeah if
you live in Portland they always talk
about it's the all the Californians are
moving to Portland and taking over
that's what they always say don't really
get me to Portland Oh yet but well
Californians are also just extending
their arm through AI and technology to
the rest of the world so California is
everywhere now
well Meghan I want to definitely talk
about kind of like more of your
profession a lot of things that that
you're that you're really stinking good
at obviously let's start with speech
pathology um but I do I guess we have to
set the stage for people who don't know
you so do you want to give a little bit
of your background like of what you know
in that in that field and like what
you've done schooling oneself so I'm
from COSO Washington obviously went to
school with Jake I originally went to
school for nursing I lived in Portland
but in a dorm room at Concordia
University I was there for a year to get
my undergrad found out really fast how
expensive a private university is I came
back to Kelso decided to do the whole
work live with my mom and do the prereqs
at our Community College Lower Columbia
um decided once I finished that I we had
to do you know take a tea's test to get
in the nursing school which I know
Shaylee knows all about I'm sure you do
too
basically have to take a test to get
into nursing school and I remember I
could not pass that test really I don't
know is it hard like how long does it
take it's not hard it's just it's math
reading writing critical thinking
science and it's on a computer and it
tells you every time you get an answer
wrong so it's almost like mentally you
get something wrong and you're like
yeah like five more wrong and I don't
pass you're so stressed yeah dude if you
only have one left in your you still
have 50 more questions yeah stress that
you're gonna feel for those other 50
questions each section so it's like
science you can only miss a certain
amount and Matt you only miss a certain
amount and so I couldn't pass that test
so I had to sit down and like really
fight with myself like because I felt
like I was feeling like I couldn't get
through school I had to sit down and say
like is this what I really want like do
I really want to be a nurse and the
answer was no III think I wanted to be a
nurse because that's what my mom did and
she could do that like support herself
fully on her own and I hope that's
something that I wanted to be able to do
as well so I sat down one summer and I
was just like I'm going to like consider
other options we were actually like my
Papa's birthday dinner and my cousin
Jessica brought up speech pathology and
I had never really heard of it I mean I
knew it was something you know there was
like a career out there about it but I
kind of researched a little bit more and
basically speech pathologist is someone
who works with either children or adults
on their speech so it can be kids with
disabilities it can be adults who've
gotten in car accidents and need to
relearn how to speak there's a lot of
different opportunities you can work in
a hospital a school have your own
private practice so I was intrigued so I
went to Portland State University and
got my undergrad in speech pathology at
the time I was so done with school
though because I think I was on your
five at that point and I was like I'm
gonna take a year off I'm gonna be the
one person it takes only one year off
and then go back one person is the one
person everyone else doesn't go back
right of course I didn't do that I
magically said while I was doing my
undergrad I was working at Starbucks and
I had what we call a regular sohe Pete
like if a person came in like daily like
we called him a regular someone who was
in Monday through Friday like 5:30 on
the dot every morning or 6 a.m. or
something like that so I had just
graduated I was quitting Starbucks her
name's Lisa mushed Jen she's actually
one of my regular customers and she had
been throughout the two year three years
I was at Starbucks constantly asking
school in my life and all these
different things very brief like
conversations yeah she's just suddenly I
feel like yeah and when you're working
the window Starbucks it like especially
at 5:30 or 6:00 in the morning you can't
be like oh the weather today it's like
alright still dark you're not awake yet
either right you know so long story
short she basically like chased me down
one day and I had no idea that she was
the director of a non-profit for a
kindergarten through seventh grade and
she wanted to hire me on as a
paraeducator specifically working with
students like who are in like speech
therapy so I kind of go out like a
little like my feet wet with that um and
yeah that's kind of my speech therapy
jig so you got into you got into the job
through the Lisa mushroom but did you
did you have schooling on speed path
speech pathology at that point yeah so
my undergrad is I have my bachelor's of
science specializing in speech and
hearing sciences so I had to do classes
like audiology phonetics I do anatomy
and physiology of the throat mouth or
throat mouth and something else so yes
the answer is yes but I wasn't like
trained in actually being like a
therapist right so but she knew probably
like okay your skills will lay into what
well and at the time I was like oh this
is perfect like I'm gonna get a job and
it's gonna be specifically working with
students or you know students who are in
speech therapy this is gonna look great
on a resume then when I go into grad
school so funny have that mindset we
have it's like it's also super
fulfilling and yeah it's great but we're
like yeah our resume needs to do just
one day we'll need that on our resume
totally well but beforehand that's that
was my ideas like oh yeah look great on
horizon it's gonna look much better than
Starbucks does look really good on your
resume though they do yes one of my good
friends who owns her own private
practice for she's a dentist and she
said if a someone who applies work to
Starbucks it's an automatic interview
those Starbucks people are such good ok
what do you think about that like like
not as just has an X Starbucks employee
like what do you think about that like
you feel like you learned some pretty
valuable things while working at
Starbucks yeah I feel Starbucks was such
a good it's changed a lot though since
I've been there I've been I was there in
oh yeah mm no like 2013 I think 2015 so
out there it's changed a lot but when I
was there Starbucks was all about the
customer it was very like the customer's
always right you need to do whatever it
takes to make the customer right we were
allowed to hand out free drinks left and
right like if you didn't make it through
the drive-through within 5 minutes we
had timers like you got free drinks like
the food wasn't free but your drinks
were gonna be Friday so I felt like it
was very you just learned very good
customer service and how to interact and
socialize with people which is a really
good people school I feel like that
business model is now biting them in the
butt I think you were fighting our whole
culture and the society in the butt
because everyone's just like entitled
Zak now no and they don't see that I've
noticed like Ali I'll be in the DRI
Starbucks drive-through and I'm thinking
like it's been eight minutes or whatever
and you know they're like not nice and I
get to the window they're just like five
ninety five and that's like it it's like
oh man oh hi or no nothing I don't know
I guess I don't have a good day
have you are you one of those people
that goes to the start like Starbucks
drive-through in the mornings no no I
like my coffee but now again I don't
know I just drink my black coffee now
and I also am someone who works in his
basement for a living so I can just walk
downstairs in a robe if I want to I
really have to go to Starbucks but I do
I do go through the drive-thru like from
time to time and I will say my
experience although it's randomly
throughout the day at random times a
random Starbucks is typically pretty
good that's a good and there's something
about though going like first thing in
the morning you can go in your robe a
lot of people did where can I go to my
birthday suit is that allowed
no well Starbucks Starbucks a change of
policy because customer is always right
no you're pinpointing me out why can't
it be naked in your Lobby in any way so
less dear alien from Starbucks and
coffee more speech pathology yes so
where we at
so I basically I went to school I did go
to school for that so I you know got my
prereqs for it I got like the base my
undergrad to be an actual speech
therapist you do have to go to graduate
school just at the time my mind was so I
was taking ooh I was thinking like for
college classes commuting to Portland
and working two jobs and so I was just
like I'm and so how we were still like
hanging out we were still fine I was
like freshly 2122 so you like we were
out every weekend just how do we survive
these things I don't know I mean I
remember I would like go out on the
nights I worked and be like at Starbucks
at what I think I'd to be there at 3:30
in the morning and I would just be like
fresh from like the bar even cuz we're
officially 20 we just smell like alcohol
one time when I was when time when I was
working at mr. formal I might've told
this one thing right in Santos podcast
but I actually I was I was very hungover
on a Sunday I was like 19 or something
at this point but I was so hungover as
us talking to this young couple who was
getting married I vomited in my mouth
like like I didn't like I was he spewed
on them or anything this is terrible but
like I had just put a hand up and say
excuse me I had to walk out of my store
like just insane but that was just who
we were when we are just wild just a
minute
once in a while you've got to go to work
a little hungover I did it more than
most people unfortunately but lesson
learned well and then as you get older
you suddenly can't do that anymore so
like Starbucks yeah like you're just
making coffee like I can do that when I
worked at cold stone I'm just scooping
ice cream I probably do that imagine
working out like like if you had to work
at Subway in the morning hungover and
smell back versus Starbucks oh man yeah
at least when I got to work I had like
free coffee all day I'm just gonna
caffeinated myself and survive I suppose
correct but yeah so I was doing a lot so
I finally was like I'm taking um at
least in my head I was taking a year off
and that was gonna meet
I'm gonna take the year and then want to
get into graduate school for speech
therapy you have to of course the GRE
exam which is basically like a pre grad
school exam you have to do a bunch of
entrance essays and interviews and all
these different things and then you also
have to have a certain grade point
average all the things so I was like I'm
gonna spend this year and I'm going to
get I'm going to take the GRE like prep
classes I'm gonna do all these you know
get my essay paper together and get
whatever I needed to do to go to grad
school but then I got hired on at family
house which um in my head was gonna be
good on my resume it was gonna be a 8 -
you know school starts at 8:00 a.m. gets
over at like what 3 and 8 to 3 p.m. job
like I'm free by 5:00 in the latest yes
working in the school helping kids doing
basically that yeah and you're naturally
good at these things too like just human
interaction and you're great at but
you're great with kids too so yeah
so that was my idea little did I know
family house is a huge community so that
I mean it's not how it played out at all
which benefited me in the future which
we'll probably get to a little bit but
yeah so then I was working with students
taking them to their speech therapy
sessions occupational therapy working
with them in the classrooms or doing
different things like teaching them like
when to raise your hand when not to or
let simple things like how to go to the
grocery store and how to make a grocery
list and what does that look like and
what doesn't you know how do you learn
money and it wasn't just it wasn't just
speech it was I was doing a few things I
was helping I mean I was helping in the
classroom because my title is a
paraeducator right but I was
specifically working with kids cuz Lisa
knew like what my goal in the end was so
she was like targeting she also wanted
to help benefit me so she's like let's
set you up with the students who are in
this and then you're gonna learn from it
so I also got to sit in on a lot of
sessions with speech therapists who are
doing the job and and most of it was
private practice so I was like well this
could be really cool cuz I could have my
own private practice my own
my own everything but yeah that was kind
of I was I did that for two years and
then it led me differently but that's
kind of my speech therapy background um
it was really good but I definitely
changed yeah yeah it's two directions I
feel like yeah like you you were thrown
into a few things you know but like you
learned so much that you probably
wouldn't have learned without that
experience like being able to have that
opportunity to like learn all the things
that you did with that I mean it's like
a like maybe it wasn't your end-all
be-all of like okay I finally have all
this money but like the the satisfaction
of that job for one and then just the I
didn't expect to learn this today about
about what I can take forward into my
future about what I can like how I can
help other kids in the future in these
ways yes and for those people who don't
know I should probably mention in family
house Academy is a I think I mentioned K
through seventh grade it is a nonprofit
at private school um it is in the middle
it's on Carol's Road so it's kind of
like surrounded by trees it's two houses
it's not an actual school so when you
walk into like the class quote-unquote
classroom it's a family room but there's
like tables for obviously for the
students do their work and there's
whiteboards but there's also a kitchen
sink and a couch and a rug and like very
comforting for so many types of people
yes it's a holistic approach so and it's
also integrated so they obviously we
have they have like grades kindergarten
through I think its seventh grade kids
kind of got the options once they got to
middle school high school de'keither
transition into public school or do you
like part time or not but what was cool
is integrated so it was based on their
level like their academic level um so
like if a second grader was you know
doing really good academically they
might move up into like the fourth grade
group because that's just where they
need to be they're a little bit higher
in the math or the English so it was
very based on that they're also heavily
based on like just physical activity
getting up and moving
and making sure like you talk out your
problems cuz it's like if a kid comes in
the room and say like I don't know their
parents are divorcing like that's
obviously the first thing that they're
gonna be thinking about the last thing
they want to do is learn what 2+2 is so
it's very like people-oriented lots of
different backgrounds so when I came
into family house I had no idea I was
just again 8 to 5 job like in the
classroom and I had no idea it's a huge
community and you can even speak on this
I would come home crying mm-hmm a lot I
would come home and be like it's so hard
it's it's just there's a lot like and it
wasn't even like that the job was hard I
mean it was hard but I I didn't know I
was getting myself into a community
which like challenged me like personally
it challenged me with students it
challenged me with my relationships I
mean we were doing so many different
things like our professional development
it was the Spartan Race Hey oh yeah yeah
dude you guys have such a good team
environment that stuff too which if you
don't know the Spartan Race it's like
what 30 obstacles I know you've done it
yeah I don't remember how many else go
with this I mean it's all an obstacle
because then you if you don't do an
obstacle you face dude I have never have
you ever done the javelin have you have
you gotten the job oh we're both that is
one thing okay so one part in this spot
Spartan Race I've done I've done so many
of these like you've done a ton yeah
like I have never once this damn javelin
you what I mean what we need to do is we
need to set up a thing in the backyard
here in me and you will just go yeah
super great at throwing javelins I don't
thanks gone it is Gerren how Darren
how's it going it I don't know I don't
quote me on that we probably should have
asked him that but all right up Jaron
has a guy that would make me feel better
right Jane if you haven't got it we're
gonna we're gonna set up a course the
mecca
don't worry apprentice so yeah so you
guys did a lot of the training I mean
that's how you would the team-building
and in connecting and
pushing each other to be the best
versions of each other obviously that's
that's pretty intense having that as
your community as your workplace
especially when you didn't know it was
like that like a lot of people would
normally be like oh I want to get in on
that but you didn't know is that so you
didn't know that I mean realistically
just who you are as a person like you
you do actually work pretty dang well
when you're being pushed and pushed I
like I mean the my first year I think I
dropped like thirty pounds and because
well I was like terrified of running
terrified so the Spartan thing like
freaked me out and we of course Lisa
like she doesn't want to start with the
suit or the what's the sprint which is
just three and a half miles she wanted
to start with a super weight super
tender the Super's limit that goes the
sprint the super the beast well cuz I
think it's 3.5 K right is this five
miles no I think it's a 5k which is
three and a half miles
oh you're right oh yeah yeah and then
the super don't quote me on that one I
think it's like eight to twelve because
the beast is supposed to be like 12 to
15 or something like they all do them
differently though I think they probably
do make the obstacle a little
differently yeah and they're all that so
they travel so this if you have an
apartment again they travel around the
u.s. and they set up obstacle courses at
like different locations so we've both
done ones at the there's a motocross
track down in Los Google yeah and so
they set it up and it's like you got to
go under barbed wire you've got it you
run five miles eight miles whatever it
is but also in between you've gotta do a
bunch of obstacles you're on like muddy
ropes
you're on all these things boulders
underneath a barbed wire carrying a
bucket of rocks for a little bit and if
you fail any things or you're not able
do able to do them you have to do
burpees it's like fifteen burpees thirty
thirty bird I know that because I did a
lot of burpees yeah horrible but it's so
satisfying once you've completed it yeah
how many do how many did you guys do as
as it oh we got our trifecta but that
was so in order to get your trifecta
metal from Spartan you have to complete
all three the super the or the sprint
the super and the beast within a within
the year so within one year you have to
all three so Lisa had us start with the
super and I was not a runner so the
thought of running
eight to 12 miles like gave me an
anxiety talk just thinking about it
well and then she's probably know you're
fine oh yeah she's like we're just gonna
go run ten miles cuz she'd be like
freaking out wakes up every Christmas
thing runs a crisp 50 she just wakes up
and runs and I always envied it yeah
they're always they're always running oh
yeah little did I know like I just had
to get out there and do it like I was
just I was all anxious about it and I
just needed to keep trying and
eventually I did it yeah right the first
few times I actually have panic attack
really like oh yeah cuz she they were so
at the family house as a team we're
training and they were like okay in
order to feel good about racing you need
to run 12 miles I which we all thought
that was me 12 miles and I remember
being at work all day like sweating cuz
I'm like 12 my I've never ran 12 miles
I've never been I think at the time I
had only ran like maybe 4 or 5 so the
thought of running 12 is just like not
happening um so she had us after we got
off work all the kids went home we put
on our running clothes and we ran from
tam-o-shanter to Lake Sacagawea over the
bridge we ran all of Lake Sacagawea back
and I remember getting to Lake Sacagawea
because at that point we're already like
I don't know how many miles is that like
4 or 5 and then the lake itself is like
three and a half miles and so I'm just
sitting here thinking like I don't know
and I had no salt so since part indeed I
had no cell phone I had no headphones I
just had me and like the people I was
with that's brutal that's like I started
like just like dry heaving I was like I
can't do this I can't finish it but the
cool part is what I learned like with
the team they like all came around me
talk to me down like talked me out of it
and I continued and guess what I
finished I think I was fine in the end
like how did you go from like okay the
thoughts that you are feeling when
you're like there's no way like these
people are not making me move like this
crazy like when you're thinking that
like how did you jump from just they
just tell you they're encouraging you
they're just we stopped that was part of
it so he stopped and I'm
literally like breathing hard and I'm
crying like I'm absolutely and I
remember I think it was Lisa and Chelsea
were just like one of them was like
rubbing my back and the other was like
you you got this like you're capable
like you've never done it before but
you're going to do it and you're going
to finish and so they just kept like the
positive mindset in my head and that was
just like okay you got to stop telling
yourself you can't like heaven my whole
head the whole time I kept thinking I
have no escape like I have no way of
like calling someone to come pick me up
I can't be seen Hey no I was like I
there's no way of getting out and so I
just kind of like panicked but then they
just continued actually I remember
Taylor at the time was behind me and he
kept every time I tried to stop he just
pushed his hand forward and like push
just not like push but they really
tapped my back just that low reminder
like I'm here I know it was like yes I'm
right behind you I kept running so yeah
I finished that and then from there on
out it honestly changed my mindset I was
like I just ran 12 mile or maim I don't
know how many miles that is I don't
remember I think it was like around 12
and I kept thinking like I can do this
like I got this so then it almost made
running easy right it's once we were
just talking about for the podcast about
running is mental it's totally mental
it's well and so we're also we were
talking about we're talking about Mount
st. Helens you've done Mount st. Helens
before yes it'd be cool I would love to
do that in the future yes oh that's
definitely yeah that's definitely a I
think I'm going to do it yeah it's
definitely mental you know like it's
it's there's no doubt that like just by
being in shape and stretching and stuff
like yeah I'm a dry enough and my body
can handle it for sure
it's mental and that I did Mount Saint
Helens I think I was 17 my dad didn't
tell me so we get your fly we're gonna
go camping and we're gonna go on a
little hike the next morning so I come
in like just a Concordia t-shirt shorts
and like my running shoes thinking like
we're long is a little hike
Oh a little did I know he wakes me up
like four or five in the morning and
he's like we're gonna go to the summit
I'm like huh and so he I was so mad at
him but it ended up being good I guess
he'd give me the socks though my feet
were like bleeding because I was in
running shoes I wasn't in hiking shoes
but no it was good
it was hard it's kind of funny I cried
for that too but I did it it was almost
like again it's mentally like great
panic and then you're fine but now like
those same moments so like at mile seven
mile nine whatever it is when you hit
that spot where you're like all I want
to do is just break down and cry right
now like now if you have that thing like
for one if you even have it you're like
I'm good I already know what I'm capable
of I'm capable of way more at least you
know and you also like even outside of
that after a while after you have a lot
of these these victories like oh I just
did this part race I did the trifecta I
did this you stopped even having those
little spots that come up we're at mile
four at Mile seven you're like I've
never in this far this is messed up I'm
panicking like this like dread that
starts happening yes it starts to go
away after you have a little more
victories yes so so you guys had a lot
of like a big team building obviously
it's a huge community at family house
yes did you guys do like what was
different about the way that you guys
taught things there then maybe a normal
public school is it yeah there's a lot
different oh don't I should have pulled
it up on my phone so I think Lisa's like
quote and I'm not gonna say it perfectly
but it's like if you educate a child you
like affect the parent
hold on I'm actually gonna pull it up
like this yeah it's really it's really
good but they're very community based so
they're the core of family House is
community service so when you sign your
child up for community service you're
assigning yourself your family up for
community service including the adults
so when I was there we had groups and
they pair you in the very beginning so
we have parent meetings and it's like
what are you gonna do this year for
community service and we each there's
like 12 groups all 12 of us have to come
up with a community service project can
be anything can be the humane society
can be picking up trash it can be a sock
donation it could be feeding the
homeless like a soup drive it can be
anything
so that part's really cool because you
get the kids involved in the community
at such a young age and I think they
kind of learn a little bit more about it
changes their scope of where they live
yeah at the time when I was there
love overwhelming was a huge topic and
debate which it's a a is for homeless um
trying to think it's an organization
that basically helps the homeless it's
like they do like food and like shell to
have shelter and clothing and all that
stuff so we were very involved with love
overwhelming but the community like
Longview coal so as a whole is very Lake
it was very debatable I think a lot of
people debated on that yeah I think I
don't even remember what that was about
but I just know that well it's no
different now because now I see online
it's a lot about the civic circle yeah
man our our town has some really gross
views on homelessness or really like a
lot of loud opinions a lot of loud jokes
a lot of I don't know are a lot of times
a small town community because we're not
we're not super small town we're big
weird I don't know it's a little hard to
explain and I guess with our town but it
does have some interesting things when
it comes to like hard opinions on things
as a whole and you know I don't believe
in that because there's this one little
thing that they do or yeah I don't know
I've been I've been kind of curious
I've been almost not wanting to dive
there's so much to know about like that
homeless camp stuff in town that I that
I like I'm like I I think to have a
proper opinion on it to know what's
really going on I would need to go down
there and talk to them I would need to
know what's going I don't even know the
ordinance like all these things I don't
have weeks and weeks of my life to have
a very solid opinion on what's going on
there and then I just don't have time to
define that to do that stuff so I don't
know I guess that sounds a little naive
but I do you really please share it
because the stuff just confuses me so
I'm like I don't know what to think
about it well because my family owns
businesses and cost a long view so as a
business owner a lot of people the
homeless
they just think of it as a negative it's
people who are on drugs people who are
leaving their garbage around people who
are alcoholics etc etc so part of it and
as a family house I did a lot with a
love overwhelming and one night we were
doing this like food drive I want to say
this around Thanksgiving time but we
were handing out like socks clothes and
food us and all the students and I had
this lady come up to me and she was
telling about her family and whatnot and
she asked me for my name was and I said
Megan she's like you just look so
familiar
and I was like oh like I mean I live
here you know small town so maybe you've
seen me around she's like what's your
last name and I'm like alum and she goes
I knew it and I'm like thinking what
like what um she was my dance teacher
when I was about five years old or not
five probably like not five probably
like seven or eight I was in top and she
was my top teacher and she's like I
remember you like like yesterday you and
your little red dress
you're my students a high step Dance
Academy Lake and I just looked at her
and she's like I have like she has six
kids or something like that her husband
and she did she got into drugs and now
she's homeless and doesn't know what to
do and just like broke my heart because
I was like I mean she said my mom used
to leave me with this person for like an
hour you know daily or few times a week
great thing is you're like you hear not
like a crazy homeless person oh nice you
help me someone
oh she needs like someone to help her
get you know get get the whatever she
needs whether that be like shelter or
rehab I'm gonna get back on her feet I
mean we all get lost I think that what
we want to do because we see these
homeless tents we see homeless people
and it makes us so uncomfortable and it
makes us like I don't know what to do
about it
I honestly it makes us feel guilty for
not doing something about it
like it's it's not a normal human trait
to walk by someone who's on the ground
starving and just keep going and pretend
you didn't see them it's weird like our
psyche is like that's not cool man
what's happening yeah so like when we
can that's why we're always judging it
or we're always having like we want to
make jokes on our Facebook about it or
we want to do these like weird things
because we're very uncomfortable by
but but I think that when we can
remember to humanize the people and and
you know whether that for me I talk
about like trying to look people in the
eyes because that's enough to remind you
yourself of like okay this is a homeless
man you know maybe he's got these this
look about him the stench about him this
whatever that like our natural things I
feel against those yeah but when you can
look him in the eye and see that there
are real human with a real human soul
yeah in there the the cures literally
personally affected you like it was she
was a teacher for you yeah and and so
you know so you obviously not that you
would before but you if you would have
had judgments toward them you would have
shattered that you've been like oh
you're not a homeless lady here
my teacher you're my dance teacher like
what so I think that it's important to
look at you know all those tents like
when you see those tents like oh like oh
that looks so trashy well inside there
is a human who was a child once who
would love who would love probably to
have a little heater next to them maybe
even some non wet sucks okay it's hard
again like I don't know like I like Here
I am not giving away all my extra socks
and walking down there and giving them
all my extra food you know whatever but
they're just like it the compassion
first like some like the comments that I
see really really make me super
uncomfortable and yeah I had to quit
reading them on Facebook I honestly
don't get on facebook facebook is a
dirty butthole it makes me so
uncomfortable yeah and then I know it's
like I get like heated and I'm just
sitting on my couch I'm not even
physically in it also
and I'm reading this status and I just
want to like so badly respond and I'm
like put your phone away just do what
I'll do is like and you know some like
it will help some people like some of my
opinions on Facebook and stuff but a lot
of times what I'll do I'll be scrolling
through I'll be scrolling through in the
five minutes and I'll get I'll get kind
of within five minutes a grasp of like
here's what people were kind of
complaining about today and then I'll
post something like here's what y'all
are doing wrong with your life right
like I'm givin opinions and yeah it does
help you people but it just kind of like
muddies into that whole thing it's just
like that's good yeah I mean I guess you
call people out for that stuff but I
don't know Facebook is a dirty dog
definitely and especially in a small
community and I'm guilt I mean we're all
guilty like so just recently my bike
stolen which was insane and of course
I'm like I live in downtown Portland so
I'm like a homeless person stole my bike
and I was complaining in this last
couple weeks because of the homeless
situation with Facebook I've been like
really thinking about it and as much as
it sucks and I was mad and angry and all
these different things like it was hope
I hope that someone who took my bike
with someone who needed a bike you know
I mean it's like I hope the person that
took it and I'm just guessing that there
was probably a homeless person like
that's like their needs of
transportation for and like they have
nowhere to go so I'm kind of like oh
like as much as like not she's hidden
goes to steal people's stuff but I don't
know I just think about that I'm like
okay at least good of my bike getting
stolen I hope that person truly needed a
bike my way of transport you know Megan
I hope that what happened was this guy
stole your bike but he had his friend
Rodney who's also homeless guy he's down
by the river and he's been making jumps
for three days and they're like dude the
jumps are almost done you got to go get
a bike and he's like rock paper scissors
Rochambeau Rodney finishes up the jumps
well whoever stole your bike stole your
bike they've been jumping it for the
last few days that's what I like to
think I'm just doing some jobs jumping
we're all out here just trying to catch
some air you know so family house we
were talking about Spartan races and OS
of course just how different family
house is from from regular public
schools you're giving us some examples
on that let's let's keep it spinning a
little bit on that because there's so
much different about family house I just
really love that I think that looking
forward into the future I guess I'm like
me I'm like when I have kids like I
don't know like do I want to go to
public schools or I want like I stress
about these things that don't exist yet
but so I'm like what could the future of
schools as a whole look like could we
have a bunch of different kinds of
schools can we have like oh my son is
this type of thinker so he goes to this
type of school like not that I really
want a bunch of segregation in our
future but it's it sparks me it's so
interesting to me and I think like
people like Lisa the motions are like
incredible and wonderful and amazing for
what they do for like pushing like just
finding new ways to teach different
types of people because we're all so
for totally it's funny because my kids
like I'm my future kids I was like never
question like just go to public school
and now like they're gonna go to private
school like kind of resigning no they're
going to private schools
no you probably want to home-school at
this point that's true I want to do it
have you seen the movie Captain
Fantastic
No we'll talk about something no no no
it's not sorry
Megan just listener so you know megan
has not seen the Marvel movies okay I
won't tell them I've seen Star Wars I'll
edit that part out so you're not so
embarrassed yeah anyway okay anyway I'm
the Aussie Thor I did see that's that's
a good thing to see oh yeah I need to
get rid of Thor though because Shaylee
she looks too long at that guy he's not
bad to look at
yeah like a bright taking just a fist
fight no problem yeah whatever he's sexy
smell you am I good um yeah so anyway
let's just keep expanding on on how it's
different I'll stop interrupting you
know and I keep going down the rabbit
hole so tell me if I'm giving that's
what a vesicle thing is just
conversation so true um the other see I
think uh actually one of my favorite I
just hit the mic sorry one of my
absolute favorite things is that the
school's integrated so there is no like
pull I mean you we pull students
obviously like to have like one-on-one
sessions if needed but for the most part
its integrated so at public schools you
have sped which is special education and
in general education it's completely
separated and there pretty much never
mixed which is insane to me it's like
insane to think about um so when I first
started working there I could not
believe like watching these other
students interact with kids with special
needs like it was normal it was normal
like there was no like how do I talk to
them how do I interact how do I it was
just like an average day like playing
communicating like helping late this kid
is different than you buddy
but like it's like there was no
difference though it's the crazy part
all right
yeah yeah not getting stuck on the fact
that they're different yeah they're
different than you that's all like in
public schools no totally and I feel
like in public schools like kids don't
know how to interact with anyone who's
different than them they're just like
stuck in their own bubbles which is I
don't know I mean I get why we do it
because of like education purposes and
whatnot and academically but so that
part was really cool to me because I had
never experienced that even as when I
was a kid so when I first was like going
into speech therapy that was one of the
things I was nervous about was like how
do you know how do you interact with
people who are different than yourself
or anything like that and just so
watching kids just be kids and like just
be themselves and not have those
barriers was really cool same with like
different grade groups so like I mean
you have kindergarteners through seventh
eighth grade if you really think about
that that's like a huge age gap and
they're all just playing just fine just
playing like the eighth graders are
playing basketball at the little ones
teaching them how to play teaching them
how to do hopscotch teaching them how to
climb a tree like and that was the other
thing too as kids could be kids like
when you go to public school like I'm in
grad school now and one of the big thing
is is I can't touch kids like you cannot
touch the kid came and pokum like can't
touch them can't hug them you can
high-five them but you can't you can't
touch them I feel like it weird ignoring
evolution at this point we're just like
hey dude weird we need to like kids need
to understand like rough-and-tumble play
the boys play is like kind of an
important thing yeah and so what family
house kids give you kids they could
climb the tree like what you could you
imagine if we like kids climb a tree in
a public school like they fell and break
the iron gate and like getting sued
what's because yeah because their mom's
gonna come in there with your finger
totally know though it's it's so hard
it's hard because with with so like with
private schools the pit like the parents
are paying for their kids to be there so
private schools have a little bit more
leeway because the parents are paying
you to be like the adult in that time so
since you're being paid that you can
like actually hug a kid or if a kid just
like if a little just needs held it for
a second because they just fell and
scraped it and you just like give them a
big hug and hold them for just a second
like it's fine sometimes a little kid
need that so when you're at a private
school like family house Academy you're
able to do those things and allow people
to be humans right and so that part was
really cool too because I felt like I
could actually like get relationships
with kids and then they started opening
up and then they would start talking and
then crazy they started learning because
their problems weren't at the forefront
of their mind anymore they're not stuck
in frightening flight oh man you have
all these kids it's like behavioral
issues at public schools but part of
it's because you put so many barriers on
them and then you just send them to like
the principal's office or you send them
to detention now you get out of school
suspension and now you're just not even
in a school then they throw you back in
and then the kids just look throwing
chairs and doing whatever and it's just
like this crazy loop cycle dude I am
just I can't stop I'm stuck on the fact
that like you can't touch the kid in it
yeah I guess you can't give him like a
hug like so okay dude so so my I mean
I'd be willing to say that like a hug
probably like saved my entire brain or
my life like well okay so like when I
was young like there was you know
probably many times where I wouldn't
feel like the connection from a lot of
things going on a traumatic childhood
like teachers I remember nurses I
remember Michelle Murie who is the miss
Maria council high school she was she
was the PE teacher when I was in
elementary school and she knew things
that were going on in depth with my
family because she like knew my family
through schooling and I mean I'm sure
she probably hugged me more times than I
can remember and she probably like made
me feel very welcome in this world
because of it I mean I don't know I just
I just imagine like these like teachers
when they know that a kid needs a hug or
he's got these things going on at home
just a little arm around just a hand on
the shoulder some serotonin release when
another human touches you it's something
that is very important that I I don't
know that's really weird that way that's
like a solid rule yeah I mean it's
created my I got I remember sixth grade
I got my babysitting license from like
the American Red Cross and my PE teacher
let me babysit her kid because she knew
I was so excited could you imagine if
someone did that now but the teacher to
get fired like there's no way you can't
like you're letting a kid into your
house you can't be with them outside of
like what's what's the end goal if we
keep adding these like
weird laws and these weird like you
can't do this and you can't do this and
you can't do this it's like it's right
doing it yeah like of Cour like I'm sure
you'll see teachers hugging kids the
problem is they're gonna hug the wrong
one so they're teaching I'm only my
first quarter undergrad school so don't
like no of course no no I know legally
and all that but that's one of the
things they're like drilling into our
heads you do not touch a kid I just
think that it kind of makes us all dance
around in fear and I don't think that's
the way and then you have these kids who
are acting out and just needing like
especially if they're not getting that
at home
imagine if they're not getting those
hugs at home or getting the height I
mean you can high-five a kid but and
then they come to school and like you're
the biggest example I can think of is
like a little so from an elementary
school and a little kindergartner has an
accident I can't help them I can't help
them I have to literally say go to the
bathroom I get that that's a weird
situation but can it just be like let it
let it pop up on a per basis level again
yeah it's like you try to solve before
it happens like that's such a
devastating thing to a kid I remember
one time in fifth grade I it was silent
reading and I sneeze and I held my nose
and I farted and it was a loudest fart
ever in the whole class laughter me in
it I was so devastated like I could if I
if I pooped my pants at that time I
probably would have been ruined and then
I can't even get a hug from a teacher
after I poop my pants now yeah it's a
rough world we're out here living in
yeah I did that too I would not poop I
didn't even know I was mrs. King I think
Calvary something like that but I puked
we're in circle time reading a story and
I was like so embarrassed to say that my
stomach hurt oh my god so embarrassed
and I just like cute everywhere in the
middle of the circle oh yeah
like you're more embarrassed away she
physically picked me up and took me to
the bathroom and like kept telling me
how it's okay and like changed me at the
time like thank you like don't make me
send my puke the whole day yeah well
because she and that's the thing as she
understands like okay this just happened
the immediately she's probably this is
terrible this is gross this sucks but
what instead she's like mother if this
girl was just willing to hide the
fact that her tummy hurt because she was
so embarrassed she's devastated by what
just happened for sure so this teacher
knew what was going on what's best for
this kid right now take care of him you
know it makes me bummed out and was my
mom happy yeah
don't make me send my puke for three
hours until she can get there from work
yeah
everybody just go outside Megan's room
now so family house is incredible we
could definitely go on about family
house forever but I do want to make sure
that we get to Ghana which is kind of
extension the family house I know the
wonderful Lisa my son led you to tell me
about Ghana Africa Meaghan oh my
goodness so that's another part of
family house they're all about culture I
mean globally minded which is amazing
and something which I didn't actually
know until I got to working at family
house which is crazy because I went to
high school and got my diploma - but did
you know they don't teach like I think
it's world history until you're in high
school I want to say like you don't
learn about anything until you're older
or it's not I can't remember the exact
term I'm a teacher but you basically
they don't teach at a young age they
aren't teaching kids about like the
world like if you pull out a map most
kids are not be able to point out the
different like countries and continents
and all that do you think it's because
they're like listen you're the lowest
you like as far as like income and
prosperity it goes like you guys are
kind of low over here so like let's just
not teach them about it until like you
know what you don't want them to be like
cool I'm seven and I'm in the poorest
country ever or whatever it is you know
yeah no I don't I don't know the
reasoning behind it because the cool
part is when we were teaching it the
kids loved it
I know it's crazy it's like why aren't
we teaching them about the world like
where they're about to go face it in
like ten years why aren't we teaching
them about it right so what we did at
family house is like each month we would
do a different hmm content I can't
remember basically but would be like
okay so this month we're doing Africa
and we'd have different like rotations
where it's like we're gonna teach you
about the music about the people about
like you
like the types of jobs they have like
what they're doing what people look like
over there like do they dress the same
do they not so very globally minded kids
were learning so many different things
Lisa's daughter went to University of
it's a main school - is the sad part I
should totally know this is it what's
the big one it's like red and yellow
like us but she went to a big college
and she has her she's a doctorate in
occupational therapy and so she had the
connection with her class and college
level went to Ghana Africa and they got
to spend like a month or something like
in a school with children with
disabilities and be like fully immersed
in their culture and like their
community so through that Lisa decided
that she was going to also do that and
she wanted to take a group of people
over and I vividly remember standing in
the school and she was like hey we're
going to Ghana Africa and like a month
like 30 days one come and I like room I
looked here and I was like huh I was
like how did like how does one do that
financially in 30 days like how it's a
funny thing that you asked me about no
way is that gonna happen oh did it
happen um we did like car washes
donations like we did a GoFundMe like
talking about it because what was cool
we which we by the way we raised money
enough money to get over there so I I
mean I paid for like some things but not
like my airfare and like where we stayed
was not very expensive so through the
donations and car washes and all that we
were able to go so I get over to Ghana
and we stayed at I cannot do not quote
me I couldn't say when I was over there
either but it's--but it's a school for
children with disabilities you have to
try it what's the name
it's like mess so beste or something
like a bad dress than em but we get over
there which is like I want to say it was
like 18
hours flight I was crazy good morning
one flight yeah we did a direct flight
from Portland to Amsterdam which was 10
hours and then we had like a huge
layover in Amsterdam and went from
Amsterdam to Ghana which was like
another eight or nine hours so it was
like a really long long flight but once
we got there we stayed at the at the
school umm Pastor Joe was the guy is the
guy who like is the director who owns it
and we get there he picks us up he
brings us to the school shows us where
we're staying and whatnot we had it was
crazy watching how the students live
like no running bathroom no running
water for the students no not a whole
lot like they just they they live in
like beds with like these you know those
like beds you used to stay at like it's
this best like those plastic mattress II
type things when you go to camp like if
you pee the bed you can just basically
but still use but we get there and oh it
was just so crazy it was so crazy to see
we get there and part of what we were
doing over there was we were gonna teach
because obviously that's what that's
what Lisa does and I was gonna work with
his jet Pastor Joe's wife was a physical
therapist or she is a physical therapist
and so I was gonna be able to kind of
see like maybe speech therapy or maybe
physical therapy maybe I don't know I
was still kind of learning at that time
but we get over there and we get into
the classroom and oh my gosh they have
these old desks that were remember the
desks when you're in like first grade
that how they're either had like the
lift lift table or like a little cubby
yeah is it like attached to the chair -
yes so they had just a bunch of those
for kids who have wheelchairs for kids
who can't walk for kids who yeah so
that's their seating no paper no pencils
no they have a whiteboard in there and
they'd give me maybe a white or dry
erase marker but maybe not might might
not have that hmm how do you teach boy
like how like how
so we we got to sit down and on a few
like of the teachers classrooms and take
notes and see like what they do and how
they do it a lot of its through dance a
lot of its through songs a lot of it was
through you know just repetition and
chanting and every now and then they
would have like a dry erase marker so
you could like physically show them and
but it was just such a crazy experience
the kids wore the same clothes every day
they would wake up in the morning and
have breakfast together which the
students made their own meals pretty
much they had one chef but everything
was cooked over a fire wait so did they
all sleep there too yeah the same stuff
so in Africa kids with disabilities are
kind of like just put away like they sew
it over in Ghana they aren't like really
a part of society as much and the
parents just kind of drop them off there
and then that's it like part of it is
once so class is they kind of learn
basically they're gonna learn like the
basics to be able to be a part of
society so they're learning some of the
basic like how to do addition and how to
do subtraction and how to read and write
a little bit but they're also gonna
teach the students how to it's like a
trade is what they called it
so in Africa they would teach like maybe
how to do beadwork so then they can make
jewelry and sell jewelry or they're
gonna teach them how to some of the kids
who didn't couldn't use their hands they
would actually be beating with their
feet it was insane so then they're
teaching them how to use their toes to
like make jewelry or how to catch fish
or how to do it's just different with
your feet but like that's I mean hey I'm
bead with my toes
watching it I was like these kid have
just so much like grit and just watching
them every day they wake up help with
their food go to class learn a few
things learn a trade go have lunch have
like free time outside which was like a
soccer field that was neat like dirt
with no net it just had like the post do
they have shoes no I mean kind of but
not really
yeah but were they what was really
grateful is gratefulness level like
where they
happy - well like would they what was so
grateful and so just like excited about
like life and no complaining like no
complaints
like they were happy to do their laundry
and they would take care of each other
so like some of the kiddos who are in
wheelchairs who can't push themselves
like the other students would like okay
like time for lunch and the kids would
just like push one another and go to
lunch and eat just be happy you'll be
late
No so they didn't have like as much
worry I fell but I mean it was
definitely a different like level of
learning in a different level of like
what was expected in Ghana versus here
so that part was cool just watching it
was life-changing to watching students
like go get their own water like go get
their own food go home do their own and
each other's laundry every day and then
like I mean I'm doing laundry for them
is actually taking laundry and then get
get water scrub it with like a brush or
sponge and then go hang it to dry it's
not like you registering in a dryer yeah
like like we get behind the laundry like
aha all these clothes I'm so gonna
wonder with all my clothes it's so bad
and then we like you and then you have
experiences like that really oh yeah you
could just have one shirt that's
actually a pillowcase with holes cut out
yes and this you just wash it with a
scrub brush every 17 days yeah or like
I'm just even like I'm one of those like
every day showers and like I like my
coffee in the morning and oh I had to
learn not I mean not to shower every day
and I had to learn the food was really
hard because everything was cooked over
like a fire so kind of happened like
that Charlie burnt taste and they ate a
lot of like like if they gave if they
gave you fish you got the whole fish so
I had like the eyeballs and the head
it's the best part oh it was real rough
I mean what we're used to is it's so
incredibly different like yeah it's it's
just downright different did it change
any of your views like like cuz of
course you knew when you're going or
like here on the flight or like this is
gonna mean wow like this is this is
gonna throw me for a loop
I know that I'm not going to have the
I'm used to having blah blah was there
was there any times when you're over
there where you're like this like like a
panic attack moment at all like like any
sort of like this is so different than
my life that like I feel uncomfortable
things are this
I never had a panic attack and I never
cried I was never like hanging out like
I need don't take this the meanest way
but like I'm surprised you didn't I know
this guy you know I don't I'm sorry if
that was rude I no no no no I didn't
take it as rude I because I think of the
same things you know I mean I didn't
have Wi-Fi I didn't have my phone I
didn't have a computer I didn't have my
car I didn't have I mean I had money but
I didn't I mean I didn't have money
because it wasn't in I forget what it's
called but whatever I thought about what
the currency is back anyons I didn't
have the things so it was just very but
you know what's funny is I almost got a
sense of everything was just so simple
and we called it Ghana time we Lisa
bring you and I were always like Ghana
time it's like everything's on Ghana
time there was no like get up at 6:00 in
the morning go work out go you know
hurry hurry rush rush rush like and
honestly throughout the day it was kind
of like work out like you weren't in a
car sitting and then at your desk
me like you were doing physical
activity all day long like you're at
work no and if you were sitting because
it was really relaxing tea was almost
kind of like a break I mean like we're
so used to just being so I but I thought
almost want to say mental break and then
like you'd be playing soccer and then
you could just like sit down for a
minute and not have anything to think
about I couldn't look at my phones
didn't have Wi-Fi distracted no didn't
have TVs so there's nothing like no TV
to watch can't watch you're forced to
just be here it's like if you don't like
here well you better deal with that
because that's all there is yeah fully
know me I mean no headphones no music no
nothing like it's just all taken from
you and you're in this but you're
surrounded by these kids who are just so
amazed by everything and so that was
rewarding and then you're surrounded by
like actual conversation so that's
rewarding and then just buy a whole new
culture so then like some of the fun
part too was like the posture would
drive us around and show us the
different communities and the different
areas of where we were in Africa I can't
wear n't we stayed in Ghana but we were
I think two hours out of a crawl which
is cut more City that's like where we
flew into is where the airport is but
that was more like rush city life but it
was there city life is very different
from our city life
like is it like what what do they like
they have electricity right yes okay I I
know that I've been to a couple places
where it's it'll be like six people on a
moped sort of thing was it like that
yeah and well unlike their quote-unquote
freeways like people would be selling
things on the freeway like carrying on
top of their heads like selling you
jewelry and selling bowls and selling
you different things so it's just very
different but I mean it was still a City
once you got out of like Accra on the
city like the roads were just roads
there was no stoplights there's no stop
signs there's no speed limit there's no
I don't even remember if there was a
yellow line it's just go you know what's
crazy about that is the difference
between that and what we have here is is
if we didn't have those things we would
we'd be like how dare you government not
take care of us how dare you not paint
the line on the ground for us we don't
know where exactly to stop like all
these little things yeah not that
everybody's like that but but it is so
like learning about the different
cultures and I mean you you seeing them
firsthand it's so crazy and it's such a
reminder of you know like we're talking
about just different mindsets when you
like seeing a homeless person like like
you the things that you're used to the
things that you accidentally take for
granted as your regular life is is
there's entire people who have never
even seen those things they've never
heard of them they've never had them in
there they're they're just as well
they're happy I know they're they're a
different kind of happy this the the way
that we live over here is not the only
way to live and I think a lot of times
we're definitely afraid of losing what
we have
but it's kind of like you know sometimes
I think from my experience losing what
you have is sometimes a good thing yeah
I think I'm just thinking forward into I
don't know I I think that a lot of our
mindset over here in the Western world
and in cities like ours is going to have
to kind of start relaxing a little bit
thinking a little more like people and
got it oh for sure cuz I think when I
was there
I've never journaled so much I was able
to journal which I don't do here what do
you remember what you wrote about what
well I got a journal I wanted to write
about I which I still have I should pull
it out because it'd probably be really
interesting to read now I wanted to
write about like my day every single day
so that way I could remember like when I
looked back what I did every day
so i journaled every day and i think i
read four books while I was there and
one month it just kinda crazy cuz now it
takes me like four months to finish a
book but it's because it's not because I
it's because I'm not making the time for
it I'm distracted by everything else
that's around me here so I just don't
make the time play well our life always
gets so much momentum no we were always
just caught up in it yeah I do want to
do that and I'm going to and it's been
three years and you forgot it existed
totally which I like the shift because I
feel like we're starting to get more
intentional because I am so just always
like pulled into great like TV Grey's
Anatomy and every all the shows just all
the shows I'm gonna I'm a TV addict so I
have to I have like turn nothing I know
dude I have all mine too I have all my
little little distractions that are like
oh it's just a few minutes in there but
but if you really let yourself like have
those few extra minutes of a book you
want to read or yeah a podcast I mean
that's something like yeah you've you've
always been in a TV but the last year or
whatever you've definitely doing more
podcast that's been slowly pushing out
TV I'm always pushing podcasts on people
like now I have once I'm done pushing on
people but it's the long-form
conversations you realize that you're
like oh yeah
nobody talks like this anymore nobody
lets each other talk nobody values each
other's opinions it's whenever we hear
two people having conversation it's
either like a fake like a show or like
something made up or it's a debate it
seems like yeah it's like what what
about just two people who maybe they're
different maybe they're friends whatever
yes having conversation about valuable
things that everybody experienced yeah
and I think people are so turned off in
the beginning because they're like a
podcast like not just I'm kind of like
reading for me like I'm like
like a lot of work and I have to find a
time to do it I like when I first moved
to Portland I had to commute from
Vancouver to Beaverton um which is one
way was like 45 minutes with traffic and
then the other way was like two hours
with traffic and so I was like well like
I got very tired of music and very tired
of the radio and I was like what am I
gonna do with my time because there's a
lot of commuting and it's a waste of
space like and I slowly got into
podcasts and then all of a sudden I was
like hooked and now it's like I like
every morning I'm like look forward to
turning on a new podcast and learning
something now me too I have like in
January we're gonna do I'm gonna do I
think I told you I'm gonna do no YouTube
I'm gonna quit YouTube okay yeah when
you said that I was like you do so
that's crazy for me but I listen is so
much YouTube right I'm not so much of a
watcher as I am yeah I was nothing more
that I was thinking more like the
podcast aspect yeah i but yeah but it's
it's funny I mean it's it's glad I'm
glad that cuz I wake up and I'm like
cool like what kind of learn about now
and it is good and I'm like I'm not
gonna punish myself for that but I do
notice my attention span like I wake up
in the morning in my like YouTube
algorithm BOTS have me so
figured out that like might within the
first 10 suggestions on my youtube
channel it's gonna be something that I'm
like oh that's a great thing to listen
to I want to check that out yeah but
it's it's very it kind of sends my
attention span like looking for new
novelty every morning and and you think
so I just kind of want to take all the
crap that I've been learning and
finished learning it for a month and not
have you - how are you gonna continue
learning it like just do what you've
already learned well well yeah so what
I'm gonna do is I have a bunch of books
that I've like either I read it or I
like make a lot of books like like like
if you read a book in a day or something
it's like it's great but you don't fully
like sometimes if you don't take your
time you don't like fully grasp it so
some of all I want to reread Reitsma
notes on so I'm gonna take this month I
reread some books I have some audio
books that I haven't finished on my
phone I'm gonna finish those I have
enough backlog of stuff to where I could
still wake up in the morning and be like
let's learn something amazing and I
could still like really enjoy what I'm
doing in the mornings but it's not just
like whatever YouTube's algorithm feeds
me yeah so that was such a millennial
question I asked you to I'm like
you don't have YouTube how you gonna
learn well I mean dude I used to be very
much addicted to social media and that's
I'm getting rid of that again too but
it's it's weird like the things that we
do a lot of times we don't really catch
ourselves that we don't catch that we're
addicted to them addicted is such a
intense word that we're like a little I
don't I'm not addicted anything that's
the weird word that's a word that
doesn't associate with me I hate that
word but I know dude my dad used to
smoke meth and so when I think of
addiction I'm like me saying addiction
next to social media is the dorkiest
thing I've ever said today so but
everyone's addicted to social media I
mean I am addicted you know we're all
very addicted to many things if you just
learn how our brains work it's it's how
it is but as you get older you start to
listen to podcasts you start to have
experiences that like you know change
your reality you start to go to places
like Ghana and see the world from
different eyes from different views from
different heights from different
temperatures like everything just
experiencing the world through different
lenses it's important I'm glad that
we've stumbled into the the learning
world of podcasts so Ghana was amazing
one of the many things that you did with
family house you have obviously
continued your career your your learning
and your going back to school now right
I am I'm back in graduate school which I
said I would never do I was always like
I'm never going back why did you say
that I was so done with school and when
I graduate in 2015 I'd done it for five
years I switched my degree or yeah I
switched my degree twice I was just done
I was like oh god like it's just a lot
of money it's a lot of effort it's a lot
of time and then at the time I was like
finally making money and able to travel
a little bit more with my friends and do
things like music festivals and you know
small things like Beach trips and all
these different things with you guys and
then I moved in with you and Shay and I
just was like I I love being like an
adult like it's just so nice to not blow
things yeah like I just going to school
was going to like alter kind of being an
adult
so in my head I was like an optimistic
oh I don't want to go back and then in
my head I was thinking like
I'll get this great job you know how you
always think you're gonna get this great
job and you're just gonna keep like
getting promoted promoted promoted
promoted a new hub all the money in the
world let's figure it out and I never
have to worry everything's good it'll be
happy you know nothing will go wrong
with that job and you won't hate it and
all these different things so that was
my mindset in late 2016 and I was not
gonna go back to school you know you're
back in school and now I Here I am back
in school but I I think it's a good
thing I feel like you're like you you
have a great job you've been but you're
you're eager I feel like what family
house like the family house was so much
for you like it was such an intense
great experience and I think it taught
you like so much at that time but I
think even like a couple years after
after family house you're now like you
know these are things that I super
valued about that place like these are
things that I do want around yeah what I
didn't realize what was happening being
younger I did not realize I had a mentor
like at all I had no idea like Lisa was
my boss she was my friend like I trusted
her obviously like she was like shaping
me into an adult like she's giving me
all these opportunities like pushing me
out of my comfort zone teaching me doing
all these amazing things and then there
was times I fought it don't get me wrong
we had hard conversations we had you
know lots of other things happening so
that which tense I'd come home like
crying some nights I mean like this is
so hard
but I had no idea that I was I had a
mentor at like the age of 21 to like 24
25 and I am so thankful for it like I
came in which i think is why I'm so
excited that I'm doing school now
because like I enjoy it it's like great
and I love learning like going to
schools not hard I don't think that
break in between was super important a
hundred we get really mean to ourselves
about those breaks like what am i doing
you know I hear it all the time but it's
totally I think it's super important
like you
totally and by the way I'm not going to
school for speech therapy I'm going for
school counseling which was not even
like a thought
my mind up until like this last year I
reach su now and so I wanted to try to
get a feel because I always had that
little medical side to me I wanted to
see like would I enjoy medical or would
I not I really enjoy what I do now it's
great a great job if you're ever
thinking about working for medical I'd
highly recommend OHSU it's a great
Hospital to work for it provides me a
lot free benefits all of it um it's just
not for me though like I don't really
enjoy working with adults which it's so
acceptable to like get to pick you know
this isn't the best thing I'm I'm like
super competitive like in my life but I
just I don't want to compete with you
over job like I just I don't like I
don't want to I just noticed all my
co-workers were always just constantly
like who's gonna get promoted into the
supervisor who's gonna get promoted and
I'm just like oh I don't wanna well
that's the thing if you gotta be able to
admit like you this is just not what I
want to be doing yeah it seems like oh
like okay everybody everybody else
around here this is what they want but
you're like I don't really have a goal
for what's gonna happen next year I'm
just me
no and yeah I know so I just really
quickly and I tried to look back what I
did was i sat down I was like when is I
most happy in my life
like like fulfilled I should say I'm
like career-wise and it was 100% I was
working at family house like I remember
as many hard moments as I was I had come
home most nights like wow like I had a
really good conversation with that kid
today like wow that kid made good
progress today I made a difference I
made a difference like that kids
comfortable with me now or I'd have like
a kid texting me being like I need help
and I'm like this kid feels comfortable
coming to me and asking me for help like
in their personal life like it was just
such a rewarding job so then I kept but
I will say I did not like teaching I did
not like lesson planning I did not like
the teaching aspect I'm really glad that
Lisa like pushed me to do it so you can
really know yeah cuz I remember what she
told me I was gonna do like a lead
teaching for like things like computers
I like looked at her and I was like huh
no I get no not and she's like yes you
are because you're really good at it so
you're gonna do it and I was like oh I
remember that first
you